{"tossups": [{"question": "This man fails to answer his car phone in the Simpsons episode \u201cBart vs. Australia,\u201d and his car is stolen from the Barbie Museum in the film<em> Rat Race</em>. Indy gets this man\u2019s autograph in<em> Indiana</em> <em>Jones and the Last Crusade</em>. Leopold Bloom and Max Bialystock put on an intentionally bad musical titled \u201cSpringtime for [this man]\u201d in<em> The Producers</em>. Fake subtitles are attached to a clip from the movie <em>Downfall</em> showing this man angrily yelling at his generals in a bunker in 1945. For the point, name this Nazi dictator.", "answer": "Adolf<b> Hitler</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In a trial resulting from this event, Kate Alterman\u2019s testimony was judged to have been memorized after Max Steuer made her repeat her story multiple times. As a result, Isaac Harris and Max Planck were acquitted of manslaughter charges stemming from this event. Locked doors on the eighth and ninth floors of the Asch building worsened this disaster, which inspired the ILGWU\u2019s fight for better working conditions in sweatshops. For the point, name this 1911 disaster in which 146 female garment workers were killed in a New York City fire.", "answer": "<b> Triangle Shirtwaist</b> Factory fire", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "During this period, the Battle of Klushino prompted a succession crisis that led Sweden to initiate the Ingrian War. The Peace of Deulino was signed during this period, in which a poor famine led to popular discontent with regent Boris Godunov. Three False Dmitris attempted to claim the throne during this period, whcih began with the ascension of the disabled Feodor and ended with the establishment of the Romanov dynasty. For the point, name this tumultuous period of early 17th century Russian history.", "answer": "<b> Time of Troubles</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This text was replaced with a description of an \u201cunjust division\u201d between male and female offspring. Al-Tabari\u2019s work includes the narrative surrounding this text, though Ibn Ishaq\u2019s work does not. This text describes al-Lat, al-Uzza, and Manat as \u201chigh-flying cranes whose intercession is hoped for,\u201d despite their status as Meccan goddesses. This text, delivered in a possibly fictitious incident, originally followed verse 20 of the Star Surah. For the point, name this controversial message, supposedly recited by Muhammad under temptation from the Devil, which inspired the title of a controversial 1988 Salman Rushdie novel.", "answer": "the<b> Satanic verses</b> (accept the<b> Story of the Cranes</b> before \u201ccranes\u201d is said; accept<b> qissat al-gharaniq</b> before \u201cgharaniq\u201d is said)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This composer finished his Piano Trio quickly so he could enlist as a truck driver in World War I, and included a \u201cForlane\u201d and \u201cRiguadon\u201d in a suite dedicated to friends who died in that war. This man wrote a piano concerto for Paul Wittgenstein, who lost a limb in World War I. This composer of<em> Le Tombeau de</em> <em>Couperin</em> also wrote a piece for Ida Rubenstein that ends with trombone glissandi and is built around a long crescendo and repetitive snare drum ostinato. For the point, name this French composer of<em> Bolero</em>.", "answer": "Maurice<b> Ravel</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Bernoulli and this man name a beam equation crucial to modern engineering, and this man finished Euclid\u2019s [yoo-klid\u2019s] connection between perfect numbers and Mersenne primes. When this man failed to build Frederick the Great a water jet, Frederick called this man \u201cCyclops,\u201d mocking his vision problems. This mathematician\u2019s analysis of the Seven Bridges of Konigsberg begat the field of graph theory. For the point, name this Swiss mathematician, honored as the namesake of the base of the natural logarithm,<em> e</em>.", "answer": "Leonhard<b> Euler</b> [oy-ler]", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {"question": "This party\u2019s youth league claimed that Helen Zille had a cabinet of men in order to \u201csleep around with them.\u201d The leader of this party has been criticized for dismissing two finance ministers within a week in December 2015. August 2016 municipal elections showed the decline of this party in the wake of Julius Malema\u2019s Economic Freedom Fighters and Mmusi Maimane\u2019s Democratic Alliance. For the point, name this party that dominates South African politics, whose members have included Jacob Zuma and Nelson Mandela.", "answer": "<b> A</b>frican<b> N</b>ational<b> C</b>ongress", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This man authorized a military seizure of Portugal-owned Goa in Operation Vijay. He declared that the \u201clight has gone out of our lives\u201d after the assassination of his mentor, Mahatma Gandhi, and his split with Muslim League leader Mohammad Ali Jinnah helped prompt the creation of Pakistan. For the point, name the first prime minister of India.", "answer": "Jawaharlal<b> Nehru</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "After hearing of this event, Philip II was said to have laughed for the only time on record. During this event, one person pleaded with his attackers to \u201crespect these grey hairs,\u201d but he was still defenestrated by the Duke of Guise. The matin bells signaled the Swiss Guards to begin this event, which was probably ordered by Catherine d\u2019Medici and took place shortly after Margaret of Anjou\u2019s marriage to Henry of Navarre. Gaspard de Coligny was killed during, for the point, what 1572 slaughter of Huguenots in Paris?", "answer": "<b> St. Bartholomew\u2019s Day Massacre</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This event is commemorated by a 200 ft tall Doric column simply known as \u201cthe Monument.\u201d The inaction of Sir Thomas Bloodworth exacerbated this event, much of which is chronicled in the diary of Samuel Pepys [peeps]. This event was blamed on French and Dutch immigrants after it was started at a bakery on Pudding Lane. Christopher Wren was commissioned to restore St. Paul\u2019s Cathedral in the aftermath of, for the point, what 1666 disaster that destroyed much of the capital of England?", "answer": "Great<b> Fire of London</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In this city, John Glover caused heavy casualties before retreating from Pell\u2019s Point. Billop\u2019s House provided the setting for a peace conference in this city prompted by the capture of John Sullivan. Richard Nicolls captured this city and maintained control of it in the Treaty of Breda. Fort Washington was in this city, and William Howe captured it in 1776 despite George Washington\u2019s defense of it. While Peter Stuyvesant led this city, it was called New Amsterdam. For the point, name this city where the Battle of Harlem Heights occurred.", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City (prompt on New Amsterdam until mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Late in life, this leader served as<em> sufet</em>, reforming the Hundred and Four \u201ccourt\u201d, until his political opponents complained to the Roman Senate that he was plotting with Antiochus the Great. Some thirty percent of the Roman Senate, as well as consul Lucius Aemilius Paullus, died in battle against this man, who used a double envelopment to crush the Roman army in 216 BC. For the point, name this leader whose victory at Cannae was not enough to defeat Rome in the Second Punic War.", "answer": "<b> Hannibal</b> Barca", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This man used his Hakkapeliitta cavalry to win the Battle of the River Lech and threaten Bavaria. A Treaty of Stettin allowed this man to occupy Pomerania as the launching ground of an invasion. This man intervened in that war after the Edict of Restitution began the persecution of Lutherans. This man defeated his rival, the Count of Tilly, at the Battle of Breitenfeld, but was killed while leading troops at the Battle of L\u00a8utzen. For the point, name this King of Sweden during the Thirty Years\u2019 War.", "answer": "<b> Gustavus Adolphus</b> (or<b> Gustav II</b> Adolf)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man attempted to move money from state banks into his \u201cindependent treasury\u201d system. John C. Calhoun\u2019s efforts to block this man from becoming Minister to Britain led this man to be appointed Vice President instead. His allegedly opulent lifestyle was attacked in Charles Ogle\u2019s Gold Spoon Oration. This man\u2019s attempt to enforce his predecessor\u2019s specie circular policy prompted the Panic of 1837, hurting his chances in the 1840 election against William Henry Harrison. For the point, name this Dutch-American president who succeeded Andrew Jackson.", "answer": "Martin<b> Van Buren</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "To demonstrate his preparedness for this event, an aging leader swam across the Yangtze river. The order to \u201cbombard the headquarters\u201d challenged existing leadership in this event, during which Deng Xiaoping [sh\u2019ow-ping] was sent away for forced labor. Participants in this event formed the Red Guard to destroy the \u201cFour Olds,\u201d which consisted of traditional and capitalist ways of thought. Mao Zedong instituted, for the point, what political movement that sought to strengthen communist spirit within China?", "answer": "Great Proletariat<b> Cultural Revolution</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This character shows a family heirloom to Mr. Lyte to prove that the two share a common ancestry, but Lyte spurns him and accuses him of thievery. This character meets his friend Rab while delivering the <em>Boston Observer</em>, and he eventually agrees to a medical procedure so he can wield Rab\u2019s gun after Rab is killed in action. This character\u2019s career as a silversmith is ruined when his hand is crippled in a smelting accident. For the point, name this boy who becomes involved in the American Independence movement in a novel by Esther Forbes.", "answer": "<b> John</b>ny<b> Tremain</b> (accept either underlined name)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "This territory\u2019s capital was established near Miles Canyon, and its oldest town was Forty Mile. This territory\u2019s namesake waterway was named after the Gwich\u2019in for \u201cwhite water river.\u201d Its Rabbit Creek was renamed during an event in which settlers used the Chilkoot and White Passes, running north from Dyea and Skagway, to travel to Dawson City, near where a precious metal was discovered in Bonanza Creek in 1896. Whitehorse is the capital of, for the point, what smallest Canadian territory, established in 1898 during the Klondike Gold Rush?", "answer": "<b> Yukon</b> Territory", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "In<em> Dickerson v. US</em>, William Rehnquist claimed that this case established policies that have become\u201cpart of our culture.\u201d This case immaterially altered the finding in<em> Escobedo v. Illinois</em> and centered around a man who confessed to rape while in police custody. This Earl Warren-written opinion noted that statements made in custody are only admissible in court under a set of conditions, including a defendant\u2019s awareness of their right to an attorney. For the point, name this 1966 Supreme Court case that led to a formal, police-given \u201cwarning\u201d of one\u2019s rights.", "answer": "<b> Miranda</b> v. Arizona (accept names in either order; accept<b> Miranda</b> rights)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man unsuccessfully besieged Marinid-held Tangier years after working with his father to seize Ceuta [thay-ooh-tah] in Morocco. This founder of the Sagres School sent Goncalo Velho to verify the location of the Azores. This son of John I funded Gil Eanes\u2019 journey to become the first European to pass Cape Bojador. The caravel ship came into widespread use under, for the point, what prince from the House of Aviz who patronized Portuguese exploration of the seas?", "answer": "Prince<b> Henry the Navigator</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The government of this country fought the Party of the Poor, led by Lucio Cabanas, in the Guerrero Mountains. In 1971, the \u201cHalcones\u201d [hal-cohn-ays] killed over 100 people, mostly students, during the Corpus Christi Massacre. Student protesters were also attacked during this country\u2019s 1968 Summer Olympics in the Tlatelolco Massacre. In 2014, 43 students commemorating that massacre were kidnapped in Iguala in this country. For the point, name this country, where students\u2019 families protested the response by President Enrique Pe\u02dcna Nieto.", "answer": "<b> Mexico</b> (or the United<b> Mexican</b> States) Page 6", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Metropolian Museum of Art is found along this region\u2019s eastern border of Fifth Avenue, called\u201cMuseum Mile.\u201d Frederick Law Olmsted and Calvert Vaux designed, for the point, what large green space in the middle of Manhattan?", "answer": "<b> Central Park</b> (prompt on Manhattan, New York City, etc. before \u201cManhattan\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "Tony Stein was awarded the Medal of Honor in this battle for creatively using the gun of a wrecked aircraft wing as a weapon. Operation Detachment called for the seizure of the South airfield in this battle, in which the largest-ever combat deployment of Marines attempted to breach Tadamichi Kuribayashi\u2019s extensive tunnel defenses. Joe Rosenthal captured an image of Marines atop Mount Suribachi during, for the point, what World War II battle, immortalized by a photo of six soldiers raising the American flag?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Iwo Jima</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This state was the named defendant in a 1976 Supreme Court case that reaffirmed the use of the death penalty; that case, brought by Troy Leon Gregg, reversed the Court\u2019s moratorium on executions imposed by its 1972 decision in<em> Furman v.</em> this state. The Eleventh Amendment was written after Alexander Chisholm attempted to sue this state, where the Yazoo land fraud took place. The 1964 Civil Rights Act\u2019s prohibitions on discrimination in private businesses was upheld after a challenge by, for the point, what U.S. state\u2019s Heart of Atlanta Motel?", "answer": "<b> Georgia</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "During the rule of this dynasty, a massive set of reforms called the New Policies were instituted by Wang Anshi. The founder of this dynasty, Taizu, greatly expanded the civil service examinations. Its naval defeat at the Battle of Yamen marked the end of its Southern phase, which began after the Jin conquest of the north around Beijing. This was the first dynasty to use gunpowder and introduce paper currency. For the point, name this Chinese dynasty that came after the Tang and was succeeded by the Mongol Yuan.", "answer": "<b> Song</b> Dynasty Page 7", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This specific statement was criticized by Kierkegaard for presupposing what it sets out to prove. The\u201cForm of the Personal\u201d theory was developed by John Macmurray to oppose this philosophical statement and its implications. This idea\u2019s predecessors included similar theories in Augustine\u2019s<em> City of God</em> and Avicenna\u2019s \u201cFloating Man\u201d thought experiment. This phrase was developed and refined in its author\u2019s <em>Meditations on First Philosophy</em> and<em> Discourse on the Method</em>. For the point, name this anti-skeptic phrase that asserts the existence of its thinker, Rene Descartes.", "answer": "\u201d<b>cogito ergo sum</b>\u201d (accept \u201c<b>I think, therefore I am</b>\u201d or \u201c<b>je pense, suis je donc</b>\u201d; prompt on partial answers, like \u201c(the) cogito\u201d)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this film stains his white hotel blanket with blood after punching a mirror. Other shots in this film cut between a murder and the slaughter of a water buffalo. In this film, Kilgore plays the <em>Ride of the Valkyries</em> and claims that he loves \u201cthe small of napalm in the morning.\u201d Martin Sheen plays Captain Willard, who travels upriver to Cambodia to kill Marlon Brando\u2019s character, Colonel Kurtz. For the point, name this Francis Ford Coppola film, loosely based on<em> Heart of Darkness</em>, about the Vietnam War,", "answer": "<b> Apocalypse Now</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {"question": "According to the Byzantine Suda, this ruler met his end by suffocation when his supporters threw too many hats and cloaks upon him. This man used the drawing of lots to fill out the ranks of his newly created Council of Four Hundred. This man promulgated the first written constitution of Athens and, according to Aristotle, used blood to write his policies, one of which instituted the death penalty for stealing a cabbage. For the point, name this Greek statesman whose name now serves as an adjective for extremely harsh laws.", "answer": "<b> Draco</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "After a massacre in this city, intelligence operatives accidentally killed the innocent Ahmed Bouchiki in Lillehammer, Norway. During a crisis in this city, Luttif Afif demanded the release of the founders of the Baader-Meinhof gang; that crisis prompted the retaliatory Operation Wrath of God against suspected Palestinian terrorists. 11 Israeli athletes were murdered by Black September operatives in, for the point, what capital of Bavaria and site of the 1972 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "<b> Munich</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "He worked with Lord Lyons to defuse tensions after the sovereignty of England was violated in the Trent affair. This man survived an attack from Lewis Powell on the same night Abraham Lincoln was assassinated. While serving under Andrew Johnson, this man\u2019s negotiations with the Russians secured a piece of land nicknamed his \u201cicebox.\u201d For the point, name this Secretary of State who purchased Alaska in 1867.", "answer": "William<b> Seward</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Augustus was forced to supervise a campaign in this region due to resistance from the Cantabrians. This region was the birthplace of both Trajan and the sword used by Roman legionaries, the<em> gladius</em>. A Roman ally in this region named Saguntum was the first city attacked by Hannibal during the Second Punic War. In this region, the Romans used hydraulic mining to extract gold at Las M\u00b4edulas and founded the modern cities of Zaragoza and Valencia. For the point, name this peninsula, the site of Roman provinces in modern day Spain.", "answer": "<b> Hispania</b> (accept<b> Hispania</b> Tarraconensis or<b> Hispania</b> Baetica; prompt on descriptions of Iberia or the Iberian Peninsula; prompt on (Roman) Spain; do not accept or prompt on Portugal or Lusitania) Page 9", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This novel\u2019s frame story involves its author finding a manuscript by Jonathan Pue while working as a customs house inspector. In this novel, supernatural powers are ascribed to Mistress Hibbins, who is the sister of the historical character Governor Richard Bellingham. In this book\u2019s climactic scene, a sermon on Election Day is delivered by Arthur Dimmesdale before he dies in his lover\u2019s arms. For the point, name this novel that begins with Hester Prynne publicly displaying the title badge of adultery, written by Nathaniel Hawthorne.", "answer": "The<b> Scarlet Letter</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "One appalled witness at this event, John Edward Taylor, was inspired to \u201cenforce the principles of civil liberty\u201d and founded the<em> Guardian</em> newspaper. Henry Hunt was scheduled to speak at this event before it was broken up by Thomas Trafford\u2019s Yeomanry. Lord Sidmouth passed the suppressive \u201cSix Acts\u201d in response to this event, in which advocates of parliamentary reform were attacked by English cavalry. For the point, name this 1819 massacre in Manchester, satirically named for the final defeat of Napoleon.", "answer": "<b> Peterloo</b> Massacre (accept equivalents for massacre)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A chemist from this country developed the first alcohol-to-volume measurement scale and names a law stating that the pressure of a gas is directly proportional to temperature. The study of chemical equilibria, including its fundamental principle, originated with a chemist from this country. Another chemist from this country discovered the first rabies vaccine, whlie another discovered the law of conservation of mass before he was guillotined. For the point, name this home country of Antoine Lavoisier [la-vwa-see-ay].", "answer": "<b> France</b>", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "A ruler of this empire discovered that his army\u2019s bowstrings had been eaten by rats during a siege of Jerusalem. The Israeli king Hoshea refused to pay tribute to this empire, prompting an invasion by Shalmaneser V years after Tiglath-Pileser III had taken this empire to its military height. The Epic of Gilgamesh was found in the library of a king of this empire, Ashurbanipal. Sennacherib ruled, for the point, what Mesopotamian empire with capital at Nineveh?", "answer": "<b> Assyria</b>n Empire (do not accept or prompt on Syria) Page 10", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This man was forced into \u201ccohabitation\u201dgovernments with conservatives like \u00b4Edouard Balladur and his successor, Jacques Chirac. For the point, name this Socialist President of 1980s France.", "answer": "Fran\u00b8cois<b> Mitterand</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man forced George Troup to replace the Treaty of Indian Springs with the Treaty of Washington after learning that unfavorable terms had been forced upon the Muscogee. As Secretary of State, this man negotiated with Luis de Onis to acquire Florida and formulated the Monroe Doctrine. This man was accused of arranging a \u201ccorrupt bargain\u201d with Henry Clay after triumphing over Andrew Jackson in the election of 1824. For the point, name this sixth U.S. president and son of the nation\u2019s second president.", "answer": "<b> J</b>ohn<b> Q</b>uincy<b> Adams</b> (prompt on Adams; do not accept or prompt on John Adams)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This organization cheered on a parade of the 3rd Cavalry Regiment immediately before that regiment turned and charged to attack them. Major General Smedley Butler declared himself a \u201cHoover For Ex-President\u201d Republican in response to his treatment of this group, which was dispersed by a combined military-police force led by Douglas MacArthur. For the point, name this group of disgruntled veterans who occupied Washington, D.C. in 1932 demanding immediate cash compensation for their World War I service.", "answer": "the<b> Bonus Army</b> (or the<b> Bonus Expeditionary Force</b>) Page 11", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this war, a piece scored for violin, cello, piano and clarinet was premiered in a POW camp; that piece was Olivier Messiaen\u2019s [mess-ay-en\u2019s]<em> Quartet for the End of Time</em>. Twelve-tone composer Anton von Webern was accidentally killed during this conflict while breaking curfew. A microtonal<em> Threnody</em> by Krysztof Penderecki [chris-toff pen-der-etz-kee] was dedicated to some of its victims, and the \u201cinvasion theme\u201d of Shostakovich\u2019s seventh symphony depicts a siege in this war. For the point, name this war, during which the<em> Leningrad</em> Symphony was written.", "answer": "<b> World War II</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man noted that pagan gods did nothing during the Battle of the Allia in a work that argued Christianity was not to blame for the later Visigoth sacking of Rome. Saint Monica dreamed that this man, her son, would return to the Christian faith if she were patient and gentle with him. After early flirtations with Manichaeism, this man served as a Christian bishop until his death in 430 AD during the Vandals\u2019 siege of Hippo. For the point, name this early Christian theologian, the author of<em> City of God</em> and his autobiographical<em> Confessions</em>.", "answer": "Saint<b> Augustine</b> of Hippo", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This event began with an order to \u201ccrack the sky and shake the earth.\u201d The Black Panther Company fought for control of the Tay Loc Airstrip during this event, which William Westmoreland believed to be a diversion for an attack on Khe Sanh. This event prompted Walter Cronkite to note that \u201cwe are mired in a stalemate,\u201d For the point, name this 1968 surprise attack on Hue, Saigon, and other cities during the Vietnamese Lunar New Year.", "answer": "<b> Tet</b> Offensive (do not prompt on Vietnam War)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "One politician from this family worked with Andrew Furuseth to sponsor an act ensuring the rights of naval workers. The civil rights advocate Belle Case married into this family, one of whose members lost a close Republican Senate primary to Joseph McCarthy. The patriarch of this family read roll calls of corrupt politicians during speeches and got seventeen percent of the vote in the 1924 Presidential election. For the point, name this family of progressive politicians from Wisconsin.", "answer": "<b> La Follette</b> (accept Robert<b> La Follette</b> Sr. and/or Jr.; accept Belle Case<b> La Follette</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man used the slogan \u201cThe People\u2019s Line\u201d to capitalize on populist support for one of his business ventures. This man protected his interest in the Accessory Transit Company by dispatching agents to Nicaragua to oust filibuster William Walker. He entered the rail industry by cornering the stock of the Harlem Railroad, and his prowess in the steamship industry led to his nickname, \u201cThe Commodore.\u201d For the point, name this industrialist who provided startup money to a Nashville university.", "answer": "Cornelius<b> Vanderbilt</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "After this empire refused to become a protectorate, its King Prempeh I was exiled to the Seychelles. This empire lost the battle of Amoaful, allowing Garnet Wolseley to capture its capital at Kumasi. Frederick Hodgson attempted to sit on the Golden Stool throne of this empire, prompting a fifth war with Great Britain that led to this empire\u2019s integration into the Gold Coast colony. Osei Tutu expanded, for the point, what empire of the Akan people, based in modern-day Ghana?", "answer": "<b> Ashanti</b> Empire (or<b> Asante</b> Empire)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A person with this first name was hired by Harry Hopkins to produce a report about Gastonia, North Carolina during the Great Depression; that journalist with this first name endured a short, turbulent marriage to Ernest Hemingway and names the Gellhorn Prize for Journalism. Another person with this first name was made wealthy by inheriting the fortune of Daniel Parke Custis. The first and third women to serve as First Lady had, for the point, what first name of George Washington\u2019s wife?", "answer": "<b> Martha</b> (accept<b> Martha</b> Gellhorn or<b> Martha</b> Washington)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Sir Humphry Davy hired this scientist as an assistant after damaging his eyesight in a lab accident. This physicist delivered the first Royal Institution Christmas Lecture and names two laws of electrolysis. This man\u2019s work on induction was mathematically formalized by James Clerk Maxwell. Electromagnetic waves are unable to enter this man\u2019s namesake \u201ccage.\u201d For the point, name this British physicist who names the SI unit of capacitance.", "answer": "Michael<b> Faraday</b>", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "This empire contributed the elephants used in the Battle of Raphia. The Bactrian kingdom expanded after the collapse of this empire, one of whose rulers inscribed edicts on tall pillars topped by lions. This empire converted to Buddhism after it fought a bloody war against Kalinga. This empire\u2019s founder fought against forces left behind by Alexander the Great and converted to Jainism before his death. For the point, name this BC-era Indian empire that was ruled by Ashoka and Chandragupta.", "answer": "<b> Maurya</b>n Empire", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "John Gibbon and Alfred Terry consolidated their forces at the Rosebud Creek prior to this battle, not knowing that George Crook\u2019s column had been defeated there prior. Prior to this battle, a commander dreamed of enemy soldiers falling from the sky like grasshoppers. Marcus Reno and Frederick Benteen\u2019s soldiers met their end against the Lakota Sioux in this battle. For the point, name this 1876 disaster for the Seventh Cavalry in which Crazy Horse defeated George Custer.", "answer": "Battle of (the)<b> Little Bighorn</b> (or the Battle of (the)<b> Greasy Grass</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A character created by this author dies in occupied Japan when a gas stove accidentally explodes. An American soldier fighting in World War II receives a watch and a letter from a British choir girl in this writer\u2019s story \u201cFor Esm\u00b4e-with Love and Squalor.\u201d In a novel by this author, the main character ice skates with Sally Hayes at Rockefeller Center and considers those around him to be \u201cphony.\u201d For the point, name this reclusive American author who created Holden Caulfield in<em> The Catcher in the Rye</em>.", "answer": "Jerome David<b> Salinger</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "A region of this state was the location of the proposed Cimmaron Territory and was officially called the \u201cPublic Land Strip.\u201d An eastern chunk of this state was proposed to be the State of Sequoyah by the Five Civilized Tribes. This state\u2019s Unassigned Lands were the subject of an 1889 land rush, and were the target of squatters known as \u201cboomers\u201d and \u201csooners.\u201d A panhandle and the former Indian Territory were part of, for the point, what 46th U.S. state just north of Texas?", "answer": "<b> Oklahoma</b> Page 15", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}